//Trivia game JS file -- week 5 homework

//global variables
var  timerCount;
var  currentQuestionNdx = 0;
var  numberOfWins = 0;
var  numberOfLoses = 0;
var  numberUnAnswered = 0;
var trivia = [{
    question: "What is the Wizard's First Rule? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Never let them see you be afraid" ,
                      "People are stupid. They will beleive a lie because they want it to be true or are afraid it might be true",
                      "Only an ordained Wizard has the power to not be corrupted by the power",
                      "Do or do not, there is no try" ],
    correctAnswer: "People are stupid. They will beleive a lie because they want it to be true or are afraid it might be true",
    },{
    question: "Who wrote the Dresdend files? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Terry Goodkind" ,
                      "Terry Brooks",
                      "Jim Butcher",
                      "J. R. R. Tolkien" ],
    correctAnswer: "Jim Butcher"
    },{
    question: "What book series was Richard Cypher in? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Magic Kingdom for Sale â€” SOLD! " ,
                      "The fellowship of the Ring",
                      "The Sword of Shannara",
                      "The Sword of Truth" ],
    correctAnswer: "The Sword of Truth"
    },{
    question: "What was the power source for the airships in the High Druid of Shannara? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Flux Capacitors" ,
                      "Dilithium Drystals",
                      "Diapson Crystals",
                      "Hot Air" ],
    correctAnswer: "Diapson Crystals"
    },{
    question: "What do the five points of Herry Dresden's pentacle repersent? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Air, fire, water, earth and sprit" ,
                      "Wind, rain, lightning, thunder and air",
                      "red, blue, green, orange and purple",
                      "mind, body, soul, life and death" ],
    correctAnswer: "Air, fire, water, earth and sprit"
    },{
    question: "What was Zeddicus Zu'l Zorander nickname? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Zuli" ,
                      "Zippy",
                      "Zedd",
                      "Zach" ],
    correctAnswer: "Zedd"
    }/*,{
    question: "6blah blah? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Never let them see you be afraid" ,
                      "People are stupid. They will beleive a lie because they want it to be true or are afraid it might be true",
                      "Only an ordained Wizard has the power to not be corrupted by the power",
                      "Do or do not, there is no try" ],
    correctAnswer: 6
    },{
    question: "7blah blah? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Never let them see you be afraid" ,
                      "People are stupid. They will beleive a lie because they want it to be true or are afraid it might be true",
                      "Only an ordained Wizard has the power to not be corrupted by the power",
                      "Do or do not, there is no try" ],
    correctAnswer: 7
    },{
    question: "8blah blah? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Never let them see you be afraid" ,
                      "People are stupid. They will beleive a lie because they want it to be true or are afraid it might be true",
                      "Only an ordained Wizard has the power to not be corrupted by the power",
                      "Do or do not, there is no try" ],
    correctAnswer: 8
    },{
    question: "9blah blah? ",
    possibleAnswers: ["Never let them see you be afraid" ,
                      "People are stupid. They will beleive a lie because they want it to be true or are afraid it might be true",
                      "Only an ordained Wizard has the power to not be corrupted by the power",
                      "Do or do not, there is no try" ],
    correctAnswer: 9
    }*/];


///event listeners

$(document).ready(function(){
    $('#resetButton').on("click", function() {
      restart();
    }) //end #resetButton').on("click"
  displayCurrentQuestion();
  }) //end of $(document).ready

//support functions
function restart(){
  $('.wins').remove();
  $('.lose').remove();
  $('.unAns').remove();
  numberOfWins = 0;
  numberOfLoses = 0;
  numberUnAnswered = 0;
  currentQuestionNdx = 0;
  displayCurrentQuestion();
}

function initGameArrayChooser(){
  for (var i = 0; i < trivia.length; i++) {
    gameArrayChooser[i] = i;
  }
}

function newEventListeners(){
  $('.possibleAnswer').on("click", function() {
    checkClickedAnswer(this.textContent);
    }) //end possibleAnswer').on("click"
}// newEventListeners()

function displayCurrentQuestion(){

  var   currentQuestion = trivia[currentQuestionNdx].question;
  //output the current question to the DOM
  $(".theCurrentQuestion").text(currentQuestion);
  //get rid of any answers from last game
  $(".answersUnOrderedList").empty();
  var answer;
  var theList = $(".answersUnOrderedList")

  for (var i = 0; i < trivia[currentQuestionNdx].possibleAnswers.length; i++) {
    answer = trivia[currentQuestionNdx].possibleAnswers[i];
    $("<li class='possibleAnswer'> " + answer + "</li>").appendTo(theList)
  }
newEventListeners();
countDownTimerObj.start();
}// end displayCurrentQuestion()

//count down timer section
var timerController;
var countDownTimerObj= {
  time:25,
  setTime:25,
  reset: function(){
    countDownTimerObj.time = countDownTimerObj.setTime;
    countDownTimerObj.updateDisplay(countDownTimerObj.time);
  },
  start: function(){
    timerController = setInterval(countDownTimerObj.count, 1000);
  },
  stop: function(){
    clearInterval(timerController);
  },
  count: function(){
    countDownTimerObj.time--;
    countDownTimerObj.updateDisplay(countDownTimerObj.time);
    //$('#display').html(countDownTimerObj.time);
  },
  inputTime: function(){
    // This line of code will grab the input from the textbox
    countDownTimerObj.setTime = $('#timeInput').val().trim();
    countDownTimerObj.time =countDownTimerObj.setTime;
    countDownTimerObj.updateDisplay(countDownTimerObj.time);
    // We have this line so that users can hit "enter" instead of clicking on ht button and it won't move to the next page
    return false;
  },
  updateDisplay: function(time){
    if (time < 7) {
      $('#timerDisplay').addClass('shortTime');
    }
    else{
      $('#timerDisplay').removeClass('shortTime');
    }
    if (time<=0) {
      $('#timerDisplay').html(time);
      this.stop();
      //if time runs out check agianst ""
      checkClickedAnswer("");
    }
    else{
      $('#timerDisplay').html(time);
    }
  }
}; //end count down timer section

//check clicked answer
function checkClickedAnswer(answerClicked){
  //added .trim() to fix leading spaces problem!!!
  if(trivia[currentQuestionNdx].correctAnswer === answerClicked.trim()){
    countDownTimerObj.stop();
    numberOfWins++;
    $('#winLose').addClass('winner');
    $('#winLose').html('&#10004');
    var resetWinLose = setTimeout(resetWL, 1500);
  }
  else if (answerClicked === "") {
    //unanswered case
    numberUnAnswered++;
    countDownTimerObj.stop();
    $('#winLose').addClass('loser');
    $('#winLose').html('X');
    var resetWinLose = setTimeout(resetWL, 1500);
  }
  else{
    numberOfLoses++;
    countDownTimerObj.stop();
    $('#winLose').addClass('loser');
    $('#winLose').html('X');
    var resetWinLose = setTimeout(resetWL, 1500);
  }
}// end check clicked answer

function resetWL(){
  $('#winLose').removeClass('winner loser');
  $('#winLose').html('');
  countDownTimerObj.reset();
  currentQuestionNdx++;
  if (currentQuestionNdx > trivia.length-1) {
    countDownTimerObj.stop();
    outputStats();
  }
  else{
    displayCurrentQuestion();
  }
}// end resetWL()

function outputStats(){
  var winText = "Number of correct answers = "+ numberOfWins;
  var loseText = "Number of wrong answers = "+ numberOfLoses;
  var unanswerText = "Number of unanswered questions = "+ numberUnAnswered;
  $('#winLose').append("<div class='wins'>"+winText+"</div>");
  $('#winLose').append("<div class='lose'>"+loseText+"</div>");
  $('#winLose').append("<div class='unAns'>"+unanswerText+"</div>")
}
